Finding Aid for University Architect's Office (University of Michigan) Records, ca. 1950-1989.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- University Buildings Files
  - Ann Arbor Campus
    - Medical Center
      - Hospitals and Clinics
        - W.K. Kellogg Eye Center
          - Costs and Contracts 1979-1986 (Box 8)
          - Eye Center-Part A (Box 9)
            - Correspondence
              - Architect 1980-1981 (Box 9)
              - University of Michigan 1980-1985 (Box 9)
            - Meeting Minutes
              - Architect 1979-1981, 2 folders (Box 9)
              - University Architect 1979-1980 (Box 9)
          - Eye Center-Part B
            - Audiovisual System 1982-1985 (Box 9)
            - Correspondence
              - Architect 1980-1985 (Box 9)
              - University of Michigan 1980-1986 (Box 9)
            - Interior Design 1982-1985 (Box 9)
            - Landscaping 1982-1984 (Box 9)
            - Meeting Minutes 1980-1983 (Box 9)
        - Operating Room and Support Space
          - General 1991 (Box 9)
            (includes photographs)
          - Budget 1990-1991
            - Contract 1990 (Box 9)
            - Meeting Notes 1990-1991 (Box 9)
            - Report-"Architectural Program: Kellogg OR and Support Space for the University of Michigan Hospitals" (Office of Plant Extension) December 12, 1990 (Box 9)
            - Reports
              - "Kellogg-Central AHU Replacement Feasibility Study" (Giffels Hoyern Basso, Inc.) August 23, 1990 (Box 9)
              - "Planning Investigation Report: Pediatrics Ophthalmology Clinic" (Planning and Design Office) November 30, 1988 (Box 9)
              - "University of Michigan Eye Center: Schematic Design for the Renovation of the Parkview/Turner Hospital" (William Kessler) May 1980 (Box 9)
              - Visual Materials undated (Box 9)
                (includes color photograph of a presentation drawing and a transparency)
        - Mott (C.S.) Children's Hospital
          - General 1960-1974, 3 folders (Box 9)
          - Cardiac Care Study Unit 1969-1972 (Box 10)
          - James L. Wilson Pediatric Laboratories 1967-1971 (Box 10)
          - Photographs circa 1967 (Box 10)
          - Reports
            - "Children's Hospital Pediatrics Unit" (Swanson Associates) May 15, 1957 (Box 10)
            - "Planning Report" (Planning Committee) 1964 (includes photographs) (Box 10)
            - "Preliminary Design Recommendations for Vertical Expansion of Passageway Between Mott and University Hospitals" (Albert Kahn Associates) August 3, 1970 (Box 10)
            - "Preliminary Report of Bid Proposals" (University Architect's Office) December 21, 1965 (Box 10)
            - "Specifications for Vertical Expansion of Passageway Between Mott and University Hospitals" (Albert Kahn Associates) 1971, 3 volumes (Box 10)
        - Outpatient Building Addition and Vertical Expansion of Passageway Between Mott and University Hospitals
          - General 1969-1973, 3 folders (Box 10)
            - Reports
              - "Briefing Book," 1970-1973 (Box 10)
              - "Outpatient Clinic Building," January 1950 (Box 10)
              - "Pre-Schematic Presentation" (University Architect's Office) March 25, 1970 (Box 10)
        - Scott and Amy Prudden Turner Memorial Clinic for Gerontology
          - General 1973-1980 (Box 10)
          - Bequest 1972-1973 (Box 10)
          - Correspondence-Architect 1974-1976 (Box 10)
          - Meeting Minutes 1974-1976 (Box 10)
          - Report
            - "Project Manual" (Warren Holmes Company and Kenneth Black) February 10, 1975 (Box 10)
        - University Hospital
          - Administrative Services Building and Parking Structure
            - General 1972-1976 (Box 10)
            - Bids and Proposals 1975 (Box 10)
            - Meeting Minutes 1975-1976 (Box 11)
            - Planning Documents 1975 (Box 11)
            - Reports
              - "Bidding Documents, Conditions of the Contract and Outline Specifications for the Proposed 'Hospital Administration Building and Parking Structure"' (Office of Plant Extension) March 3, 1975 (Box 11)
          - Ambulatory Care Facility
            - General 1961-1970 (Box 11)
            - Photographs of architectural model undated (Box 11)
            - Report-"Pre-Schematic Presentation" (University Architect's Office) April 1, 1966 (Box 11)
          - Burn Unit Renovations 1966-1971, 2 folders (Box 11)
          - Cardiac-Medical Intensive Care Unit 1966, 1969 (Box 11)
          - Elevator Renovations and Additions
            - General 1968-1970 (Box 11)
            - Report-"Final Preliminary Presentation" (University Architect's Office) June 15, 1967 (Box 11)
          - Fire Stairs Projects
            - Northeast and Southeast 1966-1970 (Box 11)
            - Northwest and Southwest 1964-1965 (Box 11)
            - Surgical Wing 1956-1964 (Box 11)
          - Inpatient Unit Modernization, Levels 10, 11, and 12
            - General 1970-1974, 2 folders (Box 11)
            - Report-"Schematic Presentation" (University Architect's Office) November 25, 1970 (Box 11)
          - Medical Procedures Unit
            - General 1987-1989 (Box 11)
            - Budget 1989-1990 (Box 11)
            - Contract 1989-1990 (Box 11)
            - Correspondence
              - Regulatory 1989 (Box 11)
              - General 1989-1990 (Box 11)
            - Meeting Minutes 1989-1990 (Box 11)
            - Photographs of Abstract Gaming Diagrams May 1989 (Box 11)
            - Regents/Governance 1988-1989 (Box 11)
            - Reports
              - "Certificate of Need," 1988 (Box 11)
              - "Planning Investigation Report" (University of Michigan Hospitals) 1988 (Box 11)
            - Schedule 1989 (Box 11)
          - Outpatient Clinic
            - Photograph Album undated (Volume 3)
            - Reports
              - "Identification and Preliminary Evaluation of University Hospital Site Alternatives" (Office of Medical Center Planning) January 1974 (Box 11)
              - "Parking Study" (Hospital Systems Engineering Services) April 1977 (Box 12)
              - "Project Report at Schematic Stage for Cardiac Study Unit, Neurosurgical Operating Suite, Women's Hospital Renovations, and Renovations for Medical-Surgical Intensive Care" (University Architect's Office and Kenneth C. Black Associates) April 8, 1969 (Box 12)
        - Women's Hospital
          - General 1968-1972 (Box 12)
            (includes Neurosurgery Operating Suite)
          - Entrance Plaza 1966 (Box 12)
          - Fire Stairs Addition 1970-1972 (Box 12)
      - Research Facilities and Institutes
        - Animal Research Facility (Unit for Laboratory Animal Medicine)
          - General 1965-1969 (Box 12)
          - Report, "Application for Health Research Facility Renovation" (University Architect's Office) February 20, 1968 (Box 12)
        - Biomedical Unit of the Highway Safety Research Institute
          - General 1966-1968 (Box 12)
          - Reports
            - "A Biomechanical-Biomedical Addition to the Highway Safety Research Institute" (Office of the President) February 7, 1967 (Box 12)
            - "Schematic Presentation" (University Architect's Office), April 12,1968 (Box 12)
        - Center for Research on Human Growth and Development
          - General 1965-1969 (Box 12)
          - Reports
            - "Proposal to Health Research Facilities Branch, National Institutes of Health: A Building for the Center for Human Growth and Development," by Robert E. Moyers (Center for Human Growth and Development) November 1, 1967, 2 folders (Box 12)
            - "Site Study for a Building for the Center for Research on Human Growth and Development," undated (Box 12)
        - Gerber Research Center 1967 (Box 12)
        - Holden Perinatal Research Building 1969-1977, 2 folders (Box 12)
        - Institute for the Study of Mental Retardation 1966-1970 (Box 12)
        - Kresge Hearing Research Institute, Report (Holabird and Root) April 12, 1961 (Box 12)
        - Medical Research Building
          - Report-"Medical Research Building," May 1950 (Box 12)
        - Medical Science Research Building I
          - General 1981-1983, 1989 (Box 12)
          - Contract 1983 (Box 12)
          - Correspondence-Architect 1981-1986 (Box 12)
          - Meeting Minutes
            - Architect 1981-1983 (Box 12)
            - University Architect 1981-1983 (Box 12)
          - Photographs of building exterior and presentation drawing undated (Box 12)
          - Pollard Institute Addition 1982
            - Reports (Box 13)
            - Feasibility Study (Jickling, Lyman and Powell) undated (Box 13)
            - Preliminary Proposal (UM Medical School) March 10, 1981 (Box 13)
        - Medical Science Research Building 11
          - General 1981-1989 (Box 13)
          - Contract 1985 (Box 13)
          - Correspondence
            - Architect 1984-1988 (Box 13)
            - University of Michigan 1984-1989 (Box 13)
          - Meeting Minutes
            - Architect 1984-1986, 1988 (Box 13)
            - University Architect 1984-1985 (Box 13)
        - Medical Science Research Building III
          - Budget 1990-1991 (Box 13)
          - Contract 1990-1994 (Box 13)
          - Correspondence
            - Construction 1991 (Box 13)
            - Extra Services 1991 (Box 13)
            - Miscellaneous Consultants 1990-1991 (Box 13)
            - Pre-Design 1989-1990 (Box 13)
            - Regulatory 1990 (Box 13)
          - Meeting Minutes 1990-1991, 2 folders (Box 13)
          - Reports
            - "Architectural Program: Medical Science Research Building III for the University of Michigan Medical School" (Office of Plant Extension) September 10, 1990 (Box 13)
        - Mental Health Research Building
          - Report-"Mental Health Research Building" (Swanson Associates) February 15, 1957 (Box 13)
        - Neuroscience Laboratory Building
          - General 1968-1971, 2 folders (Box 13)
          - Report-"Feasibility Study" (Harley, Ellington, Cowin and Stirton, Inc.) undated (Box 13)
        - Pharmacy Research Building
          - Report-"Pharmacy Research Building" (Bennett and Straight) January 28, 1959 (Box 13)
        - Upjohn Center for Clinical Pharmacology
          - General 1966-1973, 2 folders (Box 13)
          - Reports
            - "Final Preliminary Presentation" (UAO) June 19, 1967 (Box 13)
            - "Pre-Schematic Presentation" (UAO), May 26,1966 (Box 13)
            - "Schematic Presentation" (UAO) July 20, 1966 (Box 13)
            - "Schematic Presentation" (UAO), July 6 1967 (Box 13)
            - "Upjohn Center for Clinical Pharmacology" (Holabird and Root) 1968 (Box 13)
      - General
        - Child Care Center for the University of Michigan Hospitals
          - Budget 1990 (Box 13)
          - Contract 1989-1990 (Box 13)
          - Correspondence
            - Miscellaneous Consultants 1990 (Box 13)
            - Pre-Design 1987-1990 (Box 13)
            - Regulatory 1989-1991 (Box 14)
            - General 1990-1992 (Box 14)
          - Meeting Minutes 1990 (Box 14)
          - Regents' Communication, 1990. (Box 14)
          - Reports
            - "Architectural Program: Child Care Center for the University of Michigan Hospitals" (Office of Plant (Box 14)
            - Extension) March 28, 1990 "Planning Investigation Report" (Planning and Design Office), February 15, 1989 (Box 14)
        - Clinical Care and Teaching Facility (East Hospital Site) 1966-1967 (Box 14)
        - East Medical Center Parking Structure 1964-1969 (Box 14)
        - Furstenberg Student Study Center
          - General 1971-1976 (Box 14)
          - Correspondence-Architect 1971-1976 (Box 14)
          - Cost File 1972-1974 (Box 14)
          - Meeting Minutes 1972-1973 (Box 14)
          - Reports
            - "Phase I Report" (William Kessler) undated (Box 14)
            - "Phase II Report" (William Kessler) September 7, 1972 (Box 14)
            - "Specifications" (William Kessler) December 4, 1972 (Box 14)
        - Medical Records Storage Building 1964-1966 (Box 14)
        - Medical Science I
          - Report
            - "Medical Science and School of Nursing Building, First Unit; Program-Area Requirements" (Giffels and Vallet) February 1, 1955 (Box 14)
        - Medical Science II
          - General 1950-1969, 3 folders (Box 14)
          - Photograph of a presentation drawing undated (Box 14)
          - Report, "Medical Science Building-Unit II," October 1, 1963 (Box 14)
        - Medical Science III 1977-1980 (Box 14)
        - Taubman (A. Alfred) Medical Library
          - General 1974-1979, 2 folders (Box 14)
        - Taubman (A. Alfred) Medical Library (cont.)
          - Correspondence-Architect 1975-1982 (Box 15)
          - Meeting Minutes 1975-1980 (Box 15)
          - Reports
            - "Preliminary Planning Documents" (Jickling, Lyman and Powell) January 27, 1977 (Box 15)
            - "Schematic Planning" (Jickling, Lyman and Powell) September 17, 1976 (Box 15)
        - Towsley Center for Continuing Medical Education 1965-1969 (Box 15)
    - Research Facilities and Institutes
      - Highway Safety Research Institute General 1964-1970, 2 folders
        - Reports
          - "Color and Finish Schedule" (Harley, Ellington, Cowen, and Stirton, Inc.) January 5, 1968 (Box 15)
          - "Final Preliminary Design" (University Architect's Office) 1966 (Box 15)
          - "Preliminary Specifications and Schedule of Finishes: Bio-Medical Addition to Highway Safety Research Institute (Harley, Ellington, Cowen, and Stirton, Inc.) July 28, 1967 (Box 15)
          - "Pre-schematic Report" (University Architect's Office) 1966 (Box 15)
          - "Program Analysis Diagrams" (Harley, Ellington, Cowin and Stirton, Inc.) undated (Box 15)
          - "Schematic Presentation" (University Architect's Office) 1966 (Box 15)
      - Institute for Continuing Legal Education
        - General 1984-1986 (Box 15)
        - Report, "Site Study" (Hobbs and Black) September 27, 1985 (Box 15)
      - Institute of Science and Technology
        - Report (Smith, Hinchman and Grylls Associates) January 17, 1962 (Box 15)
      - Institute for Social Research
        - Addition I/Phase 1 1972-1981, 3 folders (Box 15)
        - Addition II/Phase 11 1980-1981 (Box 15)
        - Addition III/Phase 111 1979-1987 (Box 15)
        - Block Development Plan and Growth Development Study 1967-1972 (Box 15)
        - Remodeling 1973-1974 (Box 15)
        - Reports
          - 1974 Additions (Box 15)
          - 1974 additions/Alterations (Box 15)
      - National Oceanic Atmospheric Administration (Box 16)
        - General 1980-1981 (Box 16)
        - Reports
          - "Preliminary Building Program Analysis" (Winebrenner and Ebejer) January 16, 1981 (Box 16)
          - "Project Description/Design Considerations" (Winebrenner and Ebejer) undated (Box 16)
          - "Prospectus" (NOAA/UM Building Committee) April 1981, 2 volumes (Box 16)
    - Transportation and Parking
      - Ann Street Parking Structure
        - Presentation Drawing undated (Box 16)
        - Report-"Parking Structure Unit 2" (O'Dell, Hewlett and Luckenbach Associates) undated (Box 16)
      - Fletcher Street Parking Structure 1965-1969 (Box 16)
      - Forest Avenue Pedestrian Bridge 1966, 1968 (Box 16)
      - Glen Avenue Parking Structure
        - General 1985 (Box 16)
        - Correspondence 1985-1987 (Box 16)
        - Meeting Minutes 1985 (Box 16)
        - Report-"Project Description and Outline Specification" (Luckenbach and Ziegelman, Inc.) April 25, 1985 (Box 16)
      - Hill Street Parking Structure
        - General 1966-1970 (Box 16)
        - Photograph of Architectural Model (Box 16)
      - North Ingalls Parking Structure
        - Reports
          - "Proposal" (Roger Margerum, Inc.) April 23, 1985 (Box 16)
          - "Financial and Parking Management Analysis of Proposed North Ingalls Ramp and Selected Surface Lot Improvements" (BRW, Inc.) January 25, 1985 (Box 16)
      - Parking Structures-General 1962-1969
        - Reports
          - "Parking Design Criteria Study for the University of Michigan," May 8,1967 (Box 16)
          - "Parking Structure Site Study, Central campus O'Dell, Hewlett and Luckenbach Associates) May 23, 1985 (Box 16)
          - "Pedestrian Circulation Patterns and Pedestrian bridges for the Northeast Campus Area (Office of the University Architect) October 1966 (Box 16)
      - Thayer Street Parking Structure
        - Proposals 1965 (Box 16)
        - Report-"Thayer Street Parking Structure" (O'Dell, Hewlett and Luckenbach Associates) undated (Box 16)
      - West Engineering/Randall Laboratory Pedestrian Bridge 1986-1989 (Box 16)
    - General
      - Administrative Office Building
        - General 1964-1968 (Box 16)
        - Photographs-Administration Building (Fleming) circa 1970 (Box 16)
        - Report, "Schematic Presentation" (University Architect's Office) June 17, 1965 (Box 16)
      - Administrative Services Building 1974 (Box 16)
      - Alumni Center
        - Correspondence
          - Architect 1978-1982 (Box 16)
          - General 1978-1985 (Box 16)
        - Cost File 1980-1982 (Box 16)
        - Meeting Minutes 1979-1982 (Box 16)
        - Photographs (Box 16)
          (includes color negative and color slide of model and drawing)
        - Report, "Soil Investigation Report" (Soil and Materials Engineers, Inc.) 1979 (Box 16)
      - Band Practice Building 1972-1973 (Box 16)
      - Central Campus Recreation Building
        - General 1973-1981 (Box 16)
        - Meeting Minutes 1973-1976 (Box 16)
      - Civil Defense and Disaster Training Center, Report (C.W. Lane and Associates, J.H. Livingston Associates) 1957 (Box 16)
      - Computing Center
        - General 1966-1972, 2 folders (Box 16)
          (includes photographs of architectural drawings)
        - Reports
          - "A Computing Center Building for the University of Michigan," 1966 (Box 17)
          - "Final Preliminary Design" (University Architect's Office) 1969 (Box 17)
          - "Proposal to U.S. Office of Education for a Computer Center Building," 1969 (Box 17)
          - "Schematic Presentation" (University Architect's Office) 1968 (Box 17)
      - Field House Addition 1969 (Box 17)
      - Fifty-five Million Dollar Program
        - General 1965-1966 (Box 17)
        - Photograph of Architectural Model and Slides of Presentation Sketches circa 1966 (Box 17)
        - Presentation Sketches of Buildings, ca 1966, pencil on tissue paper (Box 17)
      - Food Service Building
        - General 1967-1971 (Box 17)
        - Report-"Food Service Building," undated (Box 17)
          (includes black and white photographs)
        - Heating Plant Improvements (Box 17)
        - General 1965-1971, 3 folders (Box 17)
        - Reports
          - "Report on Planning and Development," 1965 (Box 17)
          - "Water Treatment Study" (Commonwealth Associates) September 20, 1968 (Box 17)
      - Hill Auditorium Addition and Renovation
        - General
          - 1957-1958 (Box 17)
          - 1962-1968 (Box 17)
        - Reports, 3 folders
          - "Acoustical Design for Renovation and Additions for Hill Auditorium" (Paul S. Veneklasen and Associates) (Box 17)
          - Report No. 1 May 3, 1965 (Box 17)
          - Report No. 2 December 1, 1965 (Box 17)
          - "Feasibility Study-Air Conditioning," (Albert Kahn Associates) 1964 (Box 17)
          - "Proposed Alterations and Additions to Hill Auditorium" (O'Dell, Hewlett and Luckenbach Associates) 1958 (Box 17)
          - "A History of Hill Auditorium" (Ernest O. Moore for University architect's Office) 1978 (Box 17)
          - "Architectural Survey Analysis and recommendations for Renovation and Restoration of Hill Auditorium" (preliminary report) (Quinn Evans Architects) 1990 (Box 17)
          - "Feasibility Study-Hill Auditorium Restoration and Renovation (Albert Kahn associates) circa 1990 (Box 17)
      - Information Technology Building
        - General 1986 (Box 17)
        - Correspondence
          - University of Michigan 1986 (Box 17)
          - General 1986 (Box 17)
        - Reports
          - "Background Qualifications" (Tarapata, MacMahon, Paulsen Corp.) February 28, 1986 (Box 17)
          - "Interview Notes for the Information Technical Services Building" (JLP) February 28, 1986 (Box 17)
          - "Qualifications" (Luckenbach and Ziegelman, Inc.) February 28, 1986 (Box 17)
      - Laundry Building
        - Reports (Box 17)
          - "Final Preliminary Presentation" (University Architect's Office) June 15, 1968 (Box 17)
          - "Pre-schematic Presentation" (University Architect's Office) January 12, 1968 (Box 17)
      - Lorch Hall
        - General 1982-1986 (Box 17)
        - Soil Investigation 1983 (Box 17)
      - Michigan League
        - Addition 1985-1986 (Box 17)
        - Ballroom Improvements 1984-1985 (Box 17)
      - Michigan Union
        - Air Conditioning Study 1974, 1976 (Box 17)
        - Ductwork Revisions 1984-1985 (Box 17)
        - Renovations (Box 18)
          - General 1980-1983 (Box 18)
          - Meeting Minutes 1980-1981 (Box 18)
        - Report, "Michigan Union Renovation: Master Plan" (Tarapata, MacMahon, Paulsen Corp.) March 13, 1981 (Box 18)
      - Natatorium (Canham)
        - General 1986-1987 (Box 18)
        - Report, "Natatorium for the University of Michigan" (University Planner's Office and Hobbs and Black) undated (Box 18)
      - North Campus Recreation Building
        - General 1973-1974 (Box 18)
        - Brochure (Box 18)
        - Correspondence 1973-1974 (Box 18)
        - Meeting Minutes (Box 18)
        - Reports
          - "Proposed North Campus Building," (Colvin Robinson Associates) 1973 and "Site Analysis Report" (Colvin Robinson Associates), undated (Box 18)
          - "Specifications for Architectural, Mechanical, Electrical" (Colvin Robinson Associates) April 15, 1974 (Box 18)
      - Northeast Campus Planning Group 1965, 1968, 1973 (Box 18)
      - Power Center for the Performing Arts
        - Addition (Meeting Minutes) 1979-1980 (Box 18)
        - Contracts 1965-1972 (Box 18)
        - Correspondence
          - Architect 1965-1969 (Box 18)
          - Jo Mielziner Studio 1964-1968 (Box 18)
          - General 1965-1971, 1985 (Box 18)
        - Meeting Minutes 1965-1966, 1968-1971 (Box 18)
        - Photographs of Architectural Models and Construction 1980, undated (Box 18)
        - Shell 1979-1985, 2 folders (Box 18)
        - Specifications 1965 (Box 18)
      - Revelli Hall, Shepherd Wing Addition 1988-1989 (Box 18)
      - Student Activities Building-Addition-Report (Swanson Associates) February 19, 1960 (Box 18)
      - Women's Swimming Pool Building (2 photograph albums of interior and exterior) circa 1950s (Box 18)
  - Dearborn Campus
    Records of the Dearborn Campus and Flint Campus include general campus development information as well as records on specific parts of the physical plant. Documentation of these two branch campuses illustrate the planned development and growth of these campuses.
    - Campus Development
      - Classrooms and Laboratories-Architect's Correspondence 1971 (Box 18)
      - Freshman-Sophomore Instructional Facilities 1971 (Box 18)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence 1971, 1979 (Box 18)
      - Planning Study Outline 1971-1973 (Box 18)
      - Report-"Long Range Development Plan," July 20, 1973 (Box 18)
      - Support and Service Systems 1973-1974 (Box 18)
    - Classroom/Administration Building-General Correspondence 1975 (Box 18)
    - Dearborn Center
      - Reports
        - "Dearborn Center" (Giffels and Vallet, Inc., and L. Rossetti) 1957 (Box 18)